<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>html on Notes of bvfnbk</title><link>https://bvfnbk.github.io/tags/html/</link><description>Recent content in html on Notes of bvfnbk</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 10:31:44 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bvfnbk.github.io/tags/html/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A &lt;hello-message> TypeScript Web Component</title><link>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/example-web-components/ts-hello-message/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 10:31:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/example-web-components/ts-hello-message/</guid><description>A &amp;lt;hello-message&amp;gt; Web Component introduced vanilla web components using JavaScript. This is a good start but, out of reasons, using JavaScript might not be desirable.
At the moment, there is only one component and its test and just right now might be a good moment to convert the sources to TypeScript.
Preparation Create a new package and simply copy the src/public/js/HelloMessage.js to src/ts/HelloMessage.ts.
Please note: The component is basically left &amp;ldquo;as is&amp;rdquo; at the moment for the index.</description></item><item><title>Building a Webjar</title><link>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/webjars/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 14:01:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/webjars/</guid><description>Everytime when I create an application including a web-based front-end, I am thinking about the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; way to build and package its artifacts up. The choices for JVM-based artifacts are limited but front-end artifacts basically provide all file formats and scripting languages available to the platform the artifact is built upon.
Recently, I started to serve the frontend assets as static files from within my service for better or for worse.</description></item><item><title>Testing the &lt;hello-message> Web Component</title><link>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/example-web-components/testing-hello-message/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 12:34:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/example-web-components/testing-hello-message/</guid><description>The created web component (admittedly) is very simple and does not implement sophisticated behaviour (or any behaviour for that matter). It should be tested nonetheless.
The part of the software stack actually running the tests is called a test runner. Another important part is the DSL to be used to write the tests. Basically install the following packages:
karma (test runner) jasmine-core (test DSL) karma-jasmine karma-chrome-launcher karma-firefox-launcher Please note:</description></item><item><title>Overview: Web Components</title><link>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/example-web-components/overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 10:04:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/example-web-components/overview/</guid><description>Examples A &amp;lt;hello-message&amp;gt; Web Component Define a JavaScript web component. Add a watched string attribute. Update the attribute using JavaScript. Testing the &amp;lt;hello-message&amp;gt; Web Component A &amp;lt;hello-message&amp;gt; TypeScript Web Component Same as the JavaScript web component. …only using TypeScript. Test specifications from Testing the &amp;lt;hello-message&amp;gt; Web Component have been ported over. A &amp;lt;message-input&amp;gt; Web Component/posts/example-web-components/message-input/) Convert the &amp;lt;label&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;input&amp;gt; element to a dedicated component.</description></item><item><title>A &lt;hello-message> Web Component</title><link>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/example-web-components/hello-message/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 16:13:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bvfnbk.github.io/posts/example-web-components/hello-message/</guid><description>Vanilla web components are custom components written in plain JavaScript - not using any of the usual component frameworks like React, Vue or Angular and alike involved.
The following source code snippet defines a &amp;lt;hello-message /&amp;gt; component, written in plain JavaScript. It supports a single attribute named name:
Create a file src/public/js/HelloMessage.js with the following contents:
/* * Define template: * * - create `template` element * - set contents (`innerHTML`) - including `&amp;lt;style&amp;gt;` block.</description></item></channel></rss>